A Guide to the Meredith Johnson Autograph Collection, 1920-1934
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Meredith Johnson Autograph Collection 1920-1934
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
1082
This collection consists of 26 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This autograph collection, 1920-1934, 25 items, was a gift to the Library from Mr. Meredith Johnson of Charlottesville, Virginia (now a resident of Princess Anne, Maryland), on March 25, 1941.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains autographed cards or letters to Meredith Johnson or Robert Underwood Johnson.
Contents List
- Addams, Jane (1860-1935).
  Social worker. Autograph on square piece of "Hull-House" stationery
- Barrère, Camille-Eugène Pierre (1851-1940). to Robert Underwood Johnson November 29, 1930, ALS
  French diplomat.
- Brown, Elmer Ellsworth (1861-1934). May 20, 1931, TLS.
  Educator. To Robert Underwood Johnson
- Coolidge, Calvin (1872-1933)., Autographed card
  President.
- Earhart, Amelia (1897-1937)., Autographed card
  Aviator.
- Finley, John H. (1863-1940). July 14, 1932, ALS, w/photocopy of first page of JHF letter.
  Educator and Author. To Robert Underwood Johnson
- Fosdick, Harry Emerson (1878-1969)., Autographed card
  Clergyman.
- Gillette, William (1853-1937). January 6, 1934, Autographed note card
  Actor. To Meredith Johnson and Mrs. and Mrs. Holden
- Hobson, Richmond P. (1870-1937). February 6, 1931, TLS
  Admiral and Congressman. To Robert Underwood Johnson.
- Johnson, R[obert]; U[underwood](1853-1937).
  - Writer and diplomat March 20, 1920, ALS, w/envelope
    to Mrs. Susan Lawrence
  - January 25, 1931, ALS, w/envelope
    to Meredith Johnson
  - August 22, 1932, ALS, w/envelope
  - autographed note on envelope November 3, 1932
    Enclosing "piece of English heath" sent to RUJ by Sir William Watson (1858-1935; British poet) and Lady Watson
  - December 19, 1932, ALS, w/envelope
  - October 24, 1934, ALS, w/envelope
  - December 31, 1934, ALS, w/envelope
- Lindbergh, Charles A. (1902-1974). December 22, 1931, TLS
  Aviator. to Robert Underwood Johnson
- Mason, Alfred Bishop (1851-1933). December 15, 1930, ALS
  Lawyer and Author. to Meredith Johnson
- Mayo, Charles H. (1865-1939)., Autographed card
  Physician.
- Mayo, William J. (1861-1939)., Autographed card
- Pershing, John J. (1860-1948). April 11, 1931, ALS
  General. to Robert Underwood Johnson
- Rice, Alice Hegan (1870-1942)., Autographed note card to Meredith Johnson
  Novelist.
- Roosevelt, Franklin D. (1882-1945)., Autographed card "State of New York/Executive Mansion/Albany"
- Root, Elihu (1845-1937). February 25, 1931, ALS
  Lawyer and diplomat. to Robert U. Johnson
- Smith, Alfred E. (1873-1944). April 27, 1931, TLS
  Politician. to Robert Underwood Johnson